Eric Lu (Ming-Ze Lu)

https://ericluapp.com/ yksix0702@gmail.com (+44) 7708-980283

I am a senior Android engineer with 7 years of application development experience with a broad range of apps, including e-commerce, photo collage and camera app. I have solid understanding of mobile and software development cycles, and Agile methodologies. In addition, I mentor colleagues in my company. I am looking for new challenges, which I can apply these assets to continue my professional development.

SKILLS

- Android SDK, Java and Kotlin
- App performance tuning
- Mockito and Espresso testing
- RxJava and Dagger libraries

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Android Developer Yoti

Oct, 2017-present London, UK

- Delivered new features, fixed tricky issues and put a great effort into making working process smoother.
- Worked closely with design team to implement UI/UX provided and QA team to ensure the code quality produced.

Lead Engineer

Jun, 2014-Aug, 2017

Yahoo

Taipei, Taiwan

- Developed e-commerce Android applications for millions of users resulting in a 0.15% crash rate and 1s cold-start time average.
- Managed tasks within Agile methodology, cleared Sprinted tasks on schedule, and controlled JIRA workflows efficiently.
- Wrote unit and functional tests reaching a high coverage rate and fixed critical application issues.
- Proactively delivered a series of Android development tech talks and brought innovative concepts to colleagues.
- Created common Android libraries for several apps, based upon flexibility, stability and reusability of integration.

Senior Engineer ASUSTeK Computer Inc.

Nov, 2010-May, 2014 Taipei, Taiwan

- Developed applications for ASUS-branded smartphones, and collaborated with cross-functional teams to define, design and launch new software features.
- Tested code for robustness, by executing edge case, usability, and general reliability analysis.

EDUCATION

MA, Computer Science and Information Engineering National Central University

Jul, 2010 Taoyuan, Taiwan